<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>data-structure - Tag - Sayef&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
        <link>https://sayef.github.io/tags/data-structure/</link>
        <description>data-structure - Tag - Sayef&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hello@sayef.tech (Sayef)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>hello@sayef.tech (Sayef)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 04:15:37 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sayef.github.io/tags/data-structure/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Data Structure Interview Question Answers</title>
    <link>https://sayef.github.io/post/data-structure-questions/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 04:15:37 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Sayef</author>
    <guid>https://sayef.github.io/post/data-structure-questions/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1. What is data structure? A data structure is a way of organizing data that considers not only the items stored, but also their relationship to each other. Advance knowledge about the relationship between data items allows designing of efficient algorithms for the manipulation of data.
2. List out the areas in which data structures are applied extensively? Compiler Design, Operating System, Database Management System, Statistical analysis package, Numerical Analysis, Graphics, Artificial Intelligence, Simulation 3.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Linked List Basics</title>
    <link>https://sayef.github.io/post/linked-list-basics/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 04:15:37 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Sayef</author>
    <guid>https://sayef.github.io/post/linked-list-basics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A linked list is a data structure for storing, searching, manipulating and doing many more with a list of data. ‘Array’ data structure has some limitations that can be overcome easily by the linked list having some dynamic features. Let’s see what a linked list can do –
Successive elements are connected by pointers. Last element points to NULL. It can grow or shrink in size during execution of a program.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
