<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Programming - Category - Sayef&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
        <link>https://sayef.github.io/categories/programming/</link>
        <description>Programming - Category - Sayef&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hello@sayef.tech (Sayef)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>hello@sayef.tech (Sayef)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 04:15:37 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sayef.github.io/categories/programming/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Artuculation Point</title>
    <link>https://sayef.github.io/post/articulation-point/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 04:15:37 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Sayef</author>
    <guid>https://sayef.github.io/post/articulation-point/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[If a graph becomes disconnected after removal of any node (and its adjacent edges also) from the graph, then we call that node as an articulation point of the graph. In the picture, we can see that if the node d is removed, the graph is separated into two components. So it&rsquo;s an articulation point. In other words, node v is an articulation point, if there are two such nodes u and w, v node is present in every possible paths from u to v.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Basic Programming Interview Question Answers</title>
    <link>https://sayef.github.io/post/basic-programming-interview-questions/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 04:15:37 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Sayef</author>
    <guid>https://sayef.github.io/post/basic-programming-interview-questions/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is a simple collection of problems for interview from the basic knowledge of C programming.
Part 1: Write Short Procedure or Pseudo-code Write a program to print numbers from 1 to 100 without using loops. Write a C program to swap two variables without using a temporary variable. What is the 8 queens problem? Write a C program to solve it? Write a C program to print a square matrix helicaly.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Object Oriented Programming Interview Question Answers</title>
    <link>https://sayef.github.io/post/oop-interview-questions/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 04:15:37 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Sayef</author>
    <guid>https://sayef.github.io/post/oop-interview-questions/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1. What is OOPS? OOPS is abbreviated as Object Oriented Programming system in which programs are considered as a collection of objects. Each object is nothing but an instance of a class.
2. Write basic concepts of OOPS? Following are the concepts of OOPS and are as follows:.
Abstraction. Encapsulation. Inheritance. Polymorphism. 3. What is a class? A class is simply a representation of a type of object. It is the blueprint/ plan/ template that describe the details of an object.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Linked List Basics</title>
    <link>https://sayef.github.io/post/linked-list-basics/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 04:15:37 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Sayef</author>
    <guid>https://sayef.github.io/post/linked-list-basics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A linked list is a data structure for storing, searching, manipulating and doing many more with a list of data. ‘Array’ data structure has some limitations that can be overcome easily by the linked list having some dynamic features. Let’s see what a linked list can do –
Successive elements are connected by pointers. Last element points to NULL. It can grow or shrink in size during execution of a program.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
