<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>graph - Tag - Sayef&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
        <link>https://sayef.github.io/tags/graph/</link>
        <description>graph - Tag - Sayef&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hello@sayef.tech (Sayef)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>hello@sayef.tech (Sayef)</webMaster><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 04:15:37 &#43;0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sayef.github.io/tags/graph/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>&#34;Dynamic Graph CNN for Learning on Point Clouds&#34; Simplified</title>
    <link>https://sayef.github.io/post/dynamic-graph-cnn/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 04:15:37 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Sayef</author>
    <guid>https://sayef.github.io/post/dynamic-graph-cnn/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Introduction Point clouds are a collection of data points in space, usually produced by a 3D scanner. A large number of points are measured on the external surfaces of the objects and then represented as point clouds. Along with the relative 3D coordinates, point clouds can be accompanied by other pertaining features i.e. RGB or intensity. Point clouds are not the only representation of 3D space, voxel and mesh polygon are some other popular representations.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Artuculation Point</title>
    <link>https://sayef.github.io/post/articulation-point/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 04:15:37 &#43;0800</pubDate>
    <author>Sayef</author>
    <guid>https://sayef.github.io/post/articulation-point/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[If a graph becomes disconnected after removal of any node (and its adjacent edges also) from the graph, then we call that node as an articulation point of the graph. In the picture, we can see that if the node d is removed, the graph is separated into two components. So it&rsquo;s an articulation point. In other words, node v is an articulation point, if there are two such nodes u and w, v node is present in every possible paths from u to v.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
